为什么今天来
Why today?
你想听我说出来
Do you want to hear me say it?
距你上次约诊已经过了一年半
18 months since our last appointment.
你看报的吧
You read the papers?
有时看
Sometimes...
你也看电视吧
And you watch telly?
你知道我为什么来
You know why I'm here.
我来是因为...
I'm here because...
发生了什么  约翰
What happened, John?
夏...
Sherl...
你得说出来
You need to get it out.
我最好的朋友...
My best friend...
夏洛克・福尔摩斯
Sherlock Holmes...
死了
is dead.
新福尔摩斯 第2季 第3集
Sherlock S02E03 720p hdtv x264
莱辛巴赫瀑布
Falls Of The Reichenbach.
莱辛巴赫陨落
特纳[英画家]的杰作
Turner's masterpiece.
幸得寻回
Thankfully recovered,
多亏了绝世奇才夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生
owing to the prodigious talent of Mr Sherlock Holmes.
三个月前
这份小礼物代表了我们的谢意
A small token of our gratitude.
钻石袖扣  我的衬衫袖口都有扣子了
Diamond cufflinks... All my cuffs have buttons.
他是说谢谢
He means thank you.
- 我说了吗  - 快说
- Do I?  - Just say it.
- 谢谢  - 等等
- Thank you.  - Hang on.
莱辛巴赫英雄
业余侦探寻回特纳杰作
苏格兰场因遗漏线索而出丑
银行业巨头遭绑架
终于能和家人团聚
Back together with my family,
在恐怖的劫难过后
after my terrifying ordeal.
我要感谢这位帮我逃过一劫的人...
And we have one person to thank for my deliverance...
夏洛克・福尔摩斯
Sherlock Holmes.
领带夹  我从不戴领带
Tie pin. I don't wear ties.
莱辛巴赫英雄解救被绑人质
瑞科莱蒂漏网逃脱
彼得・瑞科莱蒂  自1982年起就占据了
Peter Ricoletti... Number one on Interpol's
国际刑警通缉名单榜首
most wanted list since 1982.
我们抓住了他  我们必须感谢
Well, We got him, and there's one person
这位为我们提供了决定性线索的人
we have to thank for giving us the decisive leads.
多亏了他惯用的那些手腕和才智
With all his customary diplomacy and tact.
- 反话  - 可不是
- Sarcasm.  - Yes.
我们都出钱了
We all chipped in.
把帽子戴上  把帽子戴上
Put the hat on. Put the hat on.
对  夏洛克  戴上吧
Yes, Sherlock, put it on.
凑合应付一下吧
Just get it over with.
每日明星快讯
全球独家
技术专家夏洛克再解难题
技术英雄破悬案
技术专家
"Boffin!"
技术专家夏洛克・福尔摩斯
"Boffin Sherlock Holmes!"
每人都得有一个
Everybody gets one.
- 一个什么  - 小报绰号
- One what?  - Tabloid nickname.
苏珊大妈  阴险尼克[真人秀名人]
SuBo, Nasty Nick.
也许很快我也会有一个
I'll probably get one soon.
第五页  第六栏  第一句
Page five, column six, first sentence.
为什么非要登戴帽子的照片
Why is it always the hat photograph?!
- 单身汉约翰・华生  - 这算什么帽子
- "Bachelor John Watson. "  - What kind of hat is it?
单身汉  他们到底在暗示什么
"Bachelor" What the hell are they implying?!
这算帽子吗  为什么两边都有檐
Is it a cap? Why has it got two fronts?
这是猎鹿帽
It's a deerstalker.
他身边通常都有
"Frequently seen in the company of
- 单身汉约翰・华生  - 用这帽子猎鹿
- bachelor John Watson ".  - Stalk deer with the hat.
怎么用  扔着玩
" What are you going to do, throw it?
已证实约翰・华生是单身汉
"Confirmed bachelor John Watson."
- 猎杀飞盘  - 这太过分了
- A death frisbee!  - This is too much,
- 我们得小心点了  - 上面还有垂檐
- we need to be more careful.  - It's got flaps.
遮耳垂檐  这是遮耳帽  约翰
Ear flaps, it's an ear hat, John.
你说小心点是什么意思
What do you mean, more careful?
我是说  这已经不是猎鹿帽了
I mean, this isn't a deerstalker now,
这是夏洛克・福尔摩斯的帽子
it's a Sherlock Holmes hat.
也就是说  你不再是个私家侦探了
I mean, you're not exactly a private detective any more.
- 你就快成名人了  - 会过去的
- You're this far from famous.  - It'll pass.
最好能过去  媒体风向会变  夏洛克
It better pass. The press will turn, Sherlock,
他们总变来变去  他们会转过来针对你
they always turn and they'll turn on you.
- 你真的这么在意  - 什么
- It really bothers you.  - What?
- 人们的看法  - 是的
- What people say.  - Yes.
是对我的看法  我不懂为什么你会心烦
About me? I don't understand. Why would it upset you?
你尽量保持低调就对了
Just try to keep a low profile.
这周找点小案子吧
Find yourself a little case this week.
别再上新闻
Stay out of the news.
伦敦塔
皇冠权杖
你电话响了
That's your phone.
一直响个没完
It keeps doing that.
那个  你跟他长谈过了吗
So, did you just talk to him for a really long time?
亨利・费什加没有自杀
Henry Fishguard never committed suicide.
那些伦敦警探什么都看不出来
Bow Street runners missed everything.
这案子挺急的吧
Pressing case, is it?
没解决的案子都急
They're all pressing until they're solved.
请收好您的钥匙  谢谢
Put your key back please. Thank you.
抱歉  先生
Excuse me, sir.
有金属物品吗  钥匙  手机
Any metal objects, keys, mobile phones?
你可以通过了
You can go through.
谢谢
Thank you.
要来杯茶吗  兄弟
Fancy a cuppa then, mate?
好啊  当然了
Yeah, why not?
国债收益为七
Gilts at seven.
荷兰电信暴跌  谢谢  哈维
Dutch Telecoms in free- fall. Thank you, Harvey.
英格兰银行
本顿维尔监狱
你说什么
What are you saying?
拒绝所有假释申请  并恢复死刑
Refuse them all parole and bring back the rope?
开始吧
Let's begin.
紧急情况  请离开
This is an emergency. Please leave.
先生  我必须请您离开
Sir, I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
长官  有非法闯入案件
Sir, there's been a break- in.
不在我们的职责范围
Not our division.
你肯定不想放过
You'll want it.
金库
The vault!
金库开启
居然黑了伦敦塔安保系统  怎么可能
Hacked into the Tower of bloody London's security?! How?!
就说我们马上来了
Tell them we're on our way!
又有一起  还是非法闯入
There's been another one, another break- in.
英格兰银行
Bank of England!
长官  安保系统坏了  失灵了
Sir! Security's down, sir. It's failing.
现在什么情况
What is it now?
本顿维尔监狱
Pentonville Prison.
不是吧
No!
不着急
No rush.
我来看看吧
I'll get it, shall I?
- 给你  - 现在没空  忙
- Here.  - Not now, I'm busy.
- 夏洛克  - 没空
- Sherlock...  - Not now!
他回来了
He's back.
来伦敦塔玩吧
金・莫里亚蒂
那玻璃比什么都坚硬
That glass is tougher than anything.
但比不上碳晶体  他用的是钻石
Not tougher than crystallised carbon. He used a diamond.
去找夏洛克
世纪大案
国会质疑为何伦敦塔  本顿维尔监狱  英格兰银行会同时遭到入侵
且罪犯为同一人  金姆斯・莫里亚蒂
犯罪主脑莫里亚蒂在罪案现场
用"去找夏洛克"字样涂鸦讽刺福尔摩斯
该案件引起广泛国际关注
业余侦探成为专家证人
- 准备好了  - 好了
- Ready?  - Yes.
- 福尔摩斯先生  - 退后  退后
- Mr Holmes. Mr Holmes.  - Stand back. Stand back.
- 让他们过去  - 谢谢
- Let them through.  - Thank you.
上车
Get in.
- 记住...  - 知道
- Remember...  - Yes.
- 记住...  - 知道了
记住他们告诉你的话
Remember what they told you.
- 别耍小聪明  - 不要
- Don't try to be clever.  - No.
拜托你  简单明了好不好
Please, just keep it simple and brief.
难道上庭的明星证人就不能才智超群吗
God forbid the star witness at the trial should come across intelligent.
才智可以  你那天才欠揍性格就免了
Intelligent, fine. Let's give "Smart- arse" a wide berth.
- 我该怎样还怎样  - 你有没有听我说
- I'll just be myself.  - Are you listening to me
就在今天  在贝利老街外
Today, outside the Old Bailey...
这场审判是世纪...
This is the trial of the century...
对金姆斯・莫里亚蒂的审判...
The trial of James Moriarty...
金姆斯・莫里亚蒂今天早些时候被指控...
James Moriarty, earlier today accused of...
企图盗窃王冠权杖
attempting to steal the Crown Jewels.
在贝利老街我们将见到
At the Old Bailey we have
莱辛巴赫英雄夏洛克・福尔摩斯
Reichenbach hero Sherlock Holmes...
你介意把手伸到我的口袋里吗
Would you mind slipping your hand into my pocket?
谢谢
Thanks.
莫里亚蒂王冠偷窃案
Crown Moriarty,
请前往第10法庭
please proceed to Court 10.
是你
You're him.
心水夏洛克
进错厕所了你
Wrong toilet.
- 我是你的超级粉丝  - 显而易见
- I'm a big fan.  - Evidently.
我读了你那些案子  一直在追
I read your cases, follow them all.
在我衬衫上签个名好吗
Sign my shirt, would you?
我的粉丝分两种
There are two types of fans.
有本事在下次谋杀前抓住我  这是第一种
Catch me before I kill again, Type A.
- 第二种呢  - 搭个出租就到我家了
- What's Type B?  - Your bedroom's just a taxi ride away.
你猜我是哪种
Guess which one I am?
压痕
口袋
墨水
- 都不是  - 是吗
- Neither.  - Really?
你根本不是粉丝
No, you're not a fan at all.
你前臂上的压痕  是在桌子边缘压的
Those marks on your forearm, edge of a desk.
你应该很匆忙地打了字
You've been typing in a hurry, probably,
截稿时间到了  压力巨大
pressure on, facing a deadline.
就这些
That all?
你的手腕上有墨迹
There's a smudge of ink on your wrist,
上衣口袋鼓起
a bulge in your left jacket pocket.
- 有点露馅了  - 那污点是故意弄的
- Bit of a giveaway?  - The smudge is deliberate,
你想看看我是不是像别人说的那么厉害
to see if I'm as good as they say I am.
油墨  报纸印刷用的
Oil- based, used in newspaper print.
不过是用食指涂抹的  你的手指
But drawn on with an index finger, your finger.
作为记者  你不太可能在报社沾到油墨
Journalist. Unlikely you get your hands dirty at the press.
你抹在那里是试探我
You put that there to test me.
我开始喜欢你了
I'm liking you.
我替你想好标题了
you may like a great feature,
夏洛克・福尔摩斯  帽檐下的真相
"Sherlock Holmes, the man beneath the hat".
姬蒂
Kitty...
莱利  很高兴见到你
Riley. Pleased to meet you.
不  我还是帮你免了这一问吧
Nah, I'm just saving you the job of asking.
不  我不接受采访
No, I won't give you an interview.
不  我也不需要钱
No, I don't want the money.
你和约翰・华生只是精神伴侣吗
You and John Watson, just platonic?
我能否在这个问题上也记下个不字
Can I put you down for a "No" there as well
新闻界有你们各种各样的绯闻
There's all sorts of gossip in the press about you.
迟早你会需要个和你同一战线的人
Sooner or later, you're going to need someone on your side.
一个帮你澄清流言的人
Someone to set the record straight.
你以为你能完成这种工作吗
You think you're the girl for that job, do you?
我很聪明  你可以信任我
I'm smart and you can trust me...
完全信任
totally.
聪明  好吧  调查型记者
Smart? OK, investigative journalist.
很好  看着我说出你看到什么
Good. Well, look at me and tell me what you see.
如果你能力出众  你根本不需要采访
If you're that skilful, you don't need an interview,
你可以直接读到你要的一切
you can just read what you need.
做不到吗  还是我来吧
No? OK, my turn.
我看你在寻找职业生涯第一份独家新闻
I look at you and I see someone who's still waiting for their first big scoop,
以得到编辑的关注
so their editor will notice them.
你穿了条昂贵的短裙
You're wearing an expensive skirt,
还改过两次裙边
that's been rehemmed twice.
这是你仅有的高档裙子
Only posh skirt you've got.
你的指甲  你没钱经常保养
Your nails, you can't afford to do them that often.
我看到了一个欲望强烈的人
I see someone who's hungry,
我看到的不是聪明  当然更不是可靠
I don't see smart. I definitely don't see trustworthy.
我给你句引语吧  五个字
I'll give you a quote. If you like. Three little words.
你叫我恶心
You repel me.
- 犯罪顾问  - 是的
- "A consulting criminal."  - Yes.
你能详细解释一下证词吗
Your words. Can you expand on that answer?
金姆斯・莫里亚蒂受人雇佣
James Moriarty is for hire.
- 他是个商人  - 是的
- A tradesman?  - Yes.
但不是帮你修暖气那种服务
But not the sort who'd fix your heating?
不  是帮你装炸弹或策划暗杀那种
No, the sort who'd plant a bomb or stage an assassination.
不过我猜让他修锅炉也能干得不错
But I'm sure he'd make a decent job of your boiler.
你是否会将他描述为...
Would you describe him as...
- 引导  - 什么
- Leading.  - What?
这样不行  你这是引导证人
Can't do that.  You're leading the witness.
他会反对  而法官会支持
He'll object and the judge'll uphold.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr Holmes.
问我怎么看  问我如何描述他
Ask me how, how would I describe him?
我对他有怎样的看法  他们没教过你吗
What opinion have I formed of him? They don't teach you this?
福尔摩斯先生  没有你帮忙法庭照样转
Mr Holmes, we are fine without your help.
你如何描述这个人  他的性格如何
How would you describe this man, his character?
错误一
First mistake.
金姆斯・莫里亚蒂根本不是个人
James Moriarty isn't a man at all.
他是只蜘蛛
He's a spider.
网中心的蜘蛛
A spider at the centre of a web,
这张犯罪网中有上千条线
a criminal web with a thousand threads
而他对每一条的运作
and he knows precisely
都了如指掌
how each and every single one of them dances.
- 那你们认识...  - 不  别问这问题
- And how long...? - No, no. Don't, don't do that.
- 这问题烂透了  - 福尔摩斯先生
- That's really not a good question. - Mr Holmes!
我认识他多久了  问得真不怎么样
How long have I known him? Not your best line of enquiry.
见过两次  总共五分钟
We met twice, five minutes in total.
我拿枪指着他  他想炸死我
I pulled a gun, he tried to blow me up.
好像我俩挺来电
I felt we had a special something.
索雷尔律师  你真觉得这人是个专家么
Miss Sorrel, are you seriously claiming this man is an expert?
他和被告就见过五分钟
After knowing the accused for just five minutes?
两分钟我就能看透一个人  五分钟够充裕了
Two minutes would have made me an expert, five was ample.
- 福尔摩斯先生  那由陪审团决定  - 是嘛
- Mr Holmes, that's a matter for the jury. - Really?
商人
老师
有外遇
已婚
图书管理员
一个图书管理员  两个老师
One librarian, two teachers,
两人工作压力很大  应该是金融人士
two high- pressure jobs, probably the City.
陪审团主席是医疗秘书  外国受训
The foreman's a medical secretary, trained abroad,
- 因为她的速记  - 福尔摩斯先生
- judging by her shorthand. - Mr Holmes?
七个已婚  两个在和对方搞外遇
Seven are married, two are having an affair with each other.
他们刚用完下午茶
They've just had tea and biscuits.
你想知道谁吃了威化饼么
Would you like to know who ate the wafer?
福尔摩斯先生
Mr Holmes!
传唤你来是为了回答索雷尔律师的问题
You've been called here to answer Miss Sorrel's questions,
不是让你来展示自己有多聪明
not to give us a display of your intellectual prowess.
请言简意赅地回答问题
Keep your answers brief and to the point.
否则就算你蔑视法庭
Anything else will be treated as contempt.
少显摆一会你能死么
Do you think you could survive for just a few minutes with out showing off!
我说什么来着  让你别耍小聪明
What did I say? I said don't get clever.
我又不是水龙头说关就关
I can't just turn it on and off like a tap.
- 如何  - 什么如何
- Well? - Well, what?
你不是一直在么
You were there for the whole thing,
从头到尾都在旁听
up in the gallery, start to finish.
跟你说的一样
Like you said it would be...
他靠着椅背  一直很淡定
sat on his backside, never even stirred.
莫里亚蒂根本不打算为自己辩护
Moriarty is not mounting any defence.
英格兰银行  伦敦塔  本顿维尔监狱
Bank of England, Tower of London, Pentonville.
全国最安全的三个地方
Three of the most secure places in the country
六周以前  莫里亚蒂成功闯入
and six weeks ago, Moriarty breaks in,
没人知道手法  或者原因
no- one knows how or why.
- 我们只知道...  - 他被拘留了
- All we know is... - He ended up in custody.
- 别这样  - 哪样
- Don't do that. - Do what?
- 那表情  - 啥  - 你又露出那表情了
- The look. - Look? - You're doing the look again.
我自己又看不见
Well, I can't see it, can I?
我的脸啊
It's my face.
对  而且你露出了一种
Yes and it's doing a thing, you are doing
"我们都知道到底怎么回事"的表情
"We both know what's really going on here" face.
- 确实嘛  - 我就不知道  所以我才讨厌你那表情
- We do. - No, I don't, which is why I find the face so annoying.
如果莫里亚蒂想要王冠  他可以直接拿走
If Moriarty wanted the jewels, he'd have them.
他想放走犯人  他们早就出狱了
If he wanted the prisoners freed, they'd be out on the streets.
他之所以现在还在监狱里
The only reason he's still in a prison cell right now
是因为他想要被关起来
is because he chose to be there.
这是他计划的一部分
Somehow this is part of his scheme.
克雷西尔律师  请把第一位证人传上法庭
Mr Crayhill, can we have your first witness?
法官大人  我们没有证人
Your Honour, we're not calling any witnesses.
我不懂
I don't follow.
你们不是辩方么
You've entered a plea of not guilty.
可我的当事人并未提供任何证据
Nevertheless, my client is offering no evidence.
被告陈述完毕
The defence... rests.
陪审团的各位
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
金姆斯・莫里亚蒂被控告
James Moriarty stands accused...
和多起盗窃未遂案有关
of several counts of attempted burglary.
若他罪名成立
Crimes which, if he's found guilty,
将被监禁多年
will elicit a very long custodial sentence,
可是  他的法律团队
and yet... his legal team...
却不提供任何证据
has chosen to offer no evidence
来为他进行辩护
whatsoever to support their plea.
这不寻常  但出于公正
I find myself in the unusual position
我给陪审团一个裁决建议
of recommending a verdict wholeheartedly.
你们必须判他有罪
You must find him guilty.
有罪
Guilty.
你们必须判他有罪
You must find him guilty.
开庭了
They're coming back.
才六分钟
That's six minutes.
说实话居然用了这么久
Surprised it took them that long, to be honest.
厕所排队的人真多
There's a queue for the loo!
请陪审团宣布你们一致通过的裁决
Have you reached a verdict on which you all agree?
罪名不成立  他们居然判他无罪
Not guilty, they found him not guilty.
没有辩护  莫里亚蒂无罪释放
No defence and Moriarty's walked free.
夏洛克
Sherlock?
你在听吗  他出来了
Are you listening? He's out,
你知道他会找上你  夏...
you know he'll be coming after you. Sherl...
一般人会先敲门
Most people knock.
不过我想你也不是一般人
But then, you're not most people, I suppose.
水正好开了
Kettle's just boiled.
巴赫都都会震惊的
Johann Sebastian would be appalled.
- 能坐吗  - 请
- May I? - Please.
你知道吗  巴赫临死之前
You know when he was on his deathbed, Bach,
听见自己儿子在弹奏他的作品
he heard his son at the piano playing one of his... pieces.
还没弹完男孩就不弹了
The boy stopped before he got to the end.
那个弥留之人就跳下床
The dying man jumped out of bed,
跑到钢琴边弹完了整首曲子
ran to the piano and finished it.
无法忍受未完成的乐章
Couldn't cope with an unfinished melody.
你也是  所以你才过来
Neither can you, that's why you've come.
实话说  你有那么点开心
Be honest, you're a tiny bit pleased.
什么  审判结果么
What, with the verdict?
我又回来兴风作浪了
With me, back on the streets.
每个童话故事都要有个老派的坏蛋
Every fairy tale needs a good old- fashioned villain.
你需要我  否则你屁都不是
You need me or you're nothing.
因为我们本来就很像
Because we're just alike, you and I,
只是你比我无聊
except you're boring.
你站在正义那一方
You're on the side of the angels.
当然  你控制了陪审团
You got to the jury, of course.
我都能闯入伦敦塔
I got into the Tower of London,
12间酒店房间又算什么
you think I can't worm my way into 12 hotel rooms?
有线网
Cable network.
每个房间都有私人电视屏幕
Every hotel bedroom has a personalised TV screen.
每个人都有自己的弱点
And every person has their pressure point.
如果你想让你可爱的孩子们安然无恙
就照我说的做
都有自己想保护的人
Someone that they want to protect from harm.
小菜一碟
Easy peasy.
你打算怎么做
So how are you going to do it?
毁了我
Burn me?
就是这谜题  最后的谜题
That's the problem, the final problem.
你想到是什么了吗
Have you worked out what it is yet?
最后一案到底是什么
What's the final problem?
我告诉过你  不过你仔细听了吗
I did tell you... but did you listen?
对你来说  说句"我不知道"有多困难
How hard do you find it, having to say "I don't know"?
- 我不知道  - 很聪明啊  真聪明
- I don't know. - That's clever, very clever, awfully clever.
说起聪明  你跟你那些小朋友说了吗
Speaking of clever, have you told your little friends yet?
说什么
Told them what?
- 为何我闯入那些地方却空手而回  - 没有
- Why I broke into all those places and never took anything? - No.
- 但你明白  - 当然
- But you understand? - Obviously.
那请说吧
Off you go, then.
你自己也知道  我还说什么
You want me to tell you what you already know?
不  我要你证明你知道
No, I want you to prove that you know it.
- 什么都不拿是因为你不需要  - 好
- You didn't take anything because you don't need to. - Good.
你再也不用拿任何东西了
You'll never need to take anything ever again.
很好  因为什么
Very good, because?
因为英格兰银行  伦敦塔和本顿维尔监狱
Because nothing in the Bank of England, the Tower of London
里面没有东西能比上你手里那个
or Pentonville Prison could possibly match the value of the key
能让你闯入其中的钥匙
that could get you into all three.
任何地方的任何门我都打得开
I can open any door anywhere
只要几行计算机代码就行
with a few tiny lines of computer code.
什么私人银行账户都是胡扯  全属于我
No such thing as a private bank account now, they're all mine.
已经没有秘密了  我掌控着秘密
No such thing as secrecy, I own secrecy.
核武器编码
Nuclear codes?
我随随便便就能炸了北约
I could blow up NATO in alphabetical order.
满世界都是封锁的房间  有钥匙便是国王
In a world of locked rooms, the man with the key is king.
亲爱的  你真该看看我戴王冠的样子
And honey, you should see me in a crown.
你是利用审讯宣传自己
You were advertising all through the trial,
给世人展现你的能耐
you were showing the world what you can do.
你也帮了我
And you were helping.
客户可多了  自由政府  情报组织
Big client list... rogue governments, intelligence communities,
恐怖组织
terrorist cells.
他们都想要我
They all want me.
转眼我就成了万人迷
Suddenly, I'm Mr Sex.
如果你能进入任何银行
If you can break any bank,
你还在乎什么最高价竞买人
what do you care about the highest bidder?
我不在乎  我就是爱看他们抢破头的样
I don't, I just like to watch them all competing.
"爸爸最爱的是我"  凡人真可爱
"Daddy loves me the best." Aren't ordinary people adorable?
反正你有约翰了
Well, you know, you've got John.
我也该找个同居男友才对
I should get myself a live- in one.
- 你为什么要这么做  - 肯定很有趣
- Why are you doing all of this? - It must be so funny.
你并不真的想要金钱或权力
You don't want money or power, not really.
到底为了什么
What is it all for?
我想解决那个问题
I want to solve the problem.
我们的问题
Our problem.
最后的谜题
The final problem.
就要开始了  夏洛克  坠落
It's going to start very soon, Sherlock... the fall.
fall[坠落]同有瀑布之意  在这里双关
不过别怕  坠落跟飞翔一样
But don't be scared, falling is just like flying,
不过下场只有死亡而已
except there's a more permanent destination.
我不喜欢谜语
Never liked riddles.
学着喜欢
Learn to.
因为我欠你一次坠落  夏洛克
Because I owe you a fall, Sherlock.
我  欠  你
I... owe... you.
莫里亚蒂无罪释放  中央法庭惊人的判决
惊天罪犯
如何
他如何脱罪
莫里亚蒂消失了
莱辛巴赫英雄接下来又如何
两个月后
您的卡出现问题
请稍等
感谢您的耐心
约翰
第欧根尼俱乐部
打扰下  我找麦考夫・福尔摩斯
Excuse me, I'm looking for Mycroft Holmes?
请问他在不在
Would you happen to know if he's around at all?
你听不见我说话吗
Can you not hear me?
好吧  有人知道吗
Yes, all right. Anyone?
谁知道...
Anyone at all know...
麦考夫・福尔摩斯在哪  有人叫我在这等他
where Mycroft Holmes is, I've been asked to meet him here?
没人理我  好吧
No takers, right.
我是透明的吗  你们看得见我么
Am I invisible, can you actually see me?
多谢两位  有人叫我来找麦考夫・福尔摩斯
Thanks, gents. I've been asked to meet Mycroft Holmes.
搞什么飞机
What the hell?!
传统嘛  约翰  传统界定了我们
Tradition, John, our traditions define us.
不准讲话算哪门子传统
So total silence is traditional, is it?
连句"把糖递给我"都不能说吗
You can't even say pass the sugar?
大半个外交部门
Three- quarters of the diplomatic service
和半个政府议会要员在一起喝茶
and half the government front bench all sharing one tea trolley,
这对大家都好  相信我
it's for the best, believe me.
我们可不想重演1972年的事
We don't want a repeat of... 1972.
血色星期天事件
- 不过在这可以说话  - 你看这个
- But we can talk in here. - You read this stuff?
挺有意思
Caught my eye.
周六他们要爆个猛料
Saturday, they're doing a big expose.
真好奇她从哪拿到的这些信息
I'd love to know where she got her information.
一个叫布鲁克的人  认识么
Someone called Brook. Recognise the name?
可能是校友吧
School friend, maybe?
夏洛克的校友
Of Sherlock's?
不过这不是我叫你来的原因
But that's not why I asked you here.
- 这谁  - 不认识吗
- Who's that? - Don't know?
- 不认识  - 没见过他
- No. - Never seen his face before?
他刚住到贝克街  就和你隔了两户人家
He's taken a flat in Baker Street, two doors down from you.
我正想拜访下邻居呢
I was thinking of doing a drinks thing for the neighbours.
我看还是算了
I'm not sure you'll want to.
苏莱曼尼  阿尔巴尼亚职业杀手
Sulejmani, Albanian hit squad, expertly trained killer,
就住在离你家不到20尺的地方
living less than 20 feet from your front door.
那地段很好  坐地铁很方便
Well, it's a great location. Jubilee line's handy.
- 约翰  - 这跟我有什么关系
- John... - What's it got to do with me?
德琴科・卢德米拉
Dyachenko Ludmila.
- 我好像见过她  - 俄国杀手
- Actually, I think I have seen her. - Russian killer.
住你家对面
She's taken the flat opposite.
好吧
Ok.
我有点明白你的意思了
I'm sensing a pattern here.
其实  四个国际顶级刺客都搬到了
In fact, four top international assassins relocate
221B附近
to within spitting distance of 221b.
有什么想告诉我的么
Anything you'd care to share with me?
我该搬家了吗
I'm moving?
不难猜到他们的共同之处
It's not hard to guess the common denominator, is it?
你觉得是莫里亚蒂安排的吗
You think this is Moriarty?
他跟夏洛克说他一定会回来
He promised Sherlock he'd come back.
如果这是莫里亚蒂的杰作  我们早就死了
If this was Moriarty, we'd be dead already.
如果不是莫里亚蒂  那又是谁
If not Moriarty, then who?
你既然这么担心他  怎么不去找夏洛克谈谈
Why don't you talk to Sherlock, if you're so concerned about him?
天呐  别说了
God, don't tell me.
我们之间有太多事  约翰
Too much history between us, John.
旧账  愤恨
Old scores, resentments.
偷走了他的蓝精灵  还是弄坏了他的机动战士
Nicked all his Smurfs? Broke his Action Man?
看完了
Finished.
我们都知道要发生什么  约翰
We both know what's coming, John.
莫里亚蒂不会罢休  他发誓要干掉他唯一的敌手
Moriarty is obsessed, he's sworn to destroy his only rival.
所以你要我去照看你弟弟
So you want me to watch out for your brother
就因为他不会接受你的帮助
because he won't accept your help?
希望不会太麻烦你
If it's not too much trouble?
- 借过  - 抱歉
- Excuse me. - Sorry.
夏洛克  有件怪事...
Sherlock, something weird...
怎么回事
What's going on?
- 绑架案  - 驻美大使路法斯・布卢尔
- Kidnapping. - Rufus Bruhl. The ambassador to the US.
他不是在华盛顿吗
He's in Washington, isn't he?
不是他  是他的孩子
Not him, his children.
麦斯和克劳黛  一个七岁  一个九岁
Max and Claudette, age seven and nine.
- 他们在圣艾尔代茨  - 萨里郡的豪华寄宿学校
- They're at St Aldates. - Posh boarding place in Surrey.
学校放假  其他寄宿生都回家了
School broke up, all the boarders went home.
只有几个孩子留校  就包括他俩
Just a few kids remained, including those two.
两个孩子不见了
The kids have vanished.
大使亲自指名找你
The ambassador's asked for you personally.
莱辛巴赫英雄
The Reichenbach hero.
跟名人一起办案真不错啊
Isn't it great to be working with a celebrity?
应该很快就能放你走了  谢谢
We shouldn't need to keep you for much longer. Thank you.
- 没事了  - 麦肯齐小姐是舍监  温柔点
- It's all right. - Miss MacKenzie, House Mistress. Go easy.
麦肯齐小姐  你负责学生的安全
Miss MacKenzie, you're in charge of pupil welfare,
可昨晚却有人轻易闯入
yet you left this place wide open last night.
你是白痴  喝醉了  还是同伙
What are you, an idiot, a drunk or a criminal?!
立刻  迅速  回答我
Now, quickly, tell me!
门窗都关好了
All the doors and the windows were properly bolted.
昨晚没有任何人  包括我都没进过他们的房间
No- one, not even me, went into their room last night.
你得相信我
You have to believe me!
我相信  我就是想让你快点说
I do, I just wanted you to speak quickly.
麦肯齐小姐需要个口袋呼吸
Miss MacKenzie will need to breath into a bag now.
每学期六千块
Six grand a term,
居然还不能保证孩子的安全
you'd expect them to keep the kids safe for you.
你说其他的孩子都放假走了
You said the other kids had all left on their holidays.
只有他们俩还住在这层楼上
They were the only two sleeping on this floor.
完全没有强行闯入的迹象
There's absolutely no sign of a break- in.
闯入者肯定是藏在什么地方了
The intruder must have been hidden inside some place.
格林童话
带我去哥哥的房间
Show me where the brother slept.
小男孩每晚都睡在这儿
The boy sleeps there every night.
盯着从走廊投进来的唯一光线
Gazing at the only light source outside in the corridor.
他会认出每个人的形态和轮廓
He'd recognise every shape, every outline,
每一个走到门前的人的剪影
the silhouette of everyone who came to the door.
那又如何
OK, so?
那样  如果有一个他没见过的人走到门前
So if someone approaches the door who he doesn't recognise,
就知道是闯入者  或许他都能看到武器的轮廓
an intruder, maybe he can even see the outline of a weapon.
他会怎么做
What would he do?
在他们闯进来之前珍贵的几秒钟内
In the precious few seconds before they came into the room,
他如果没有大声呼救  会怎么做
how would he use them if not to cry out?
这个小男孩  就是这个小男孩
This little boy, this particular little boy,
他读了那么多间谍小说  他会怎么做
who reads all of those spy books, what would he do?
留下什么标记吗
He'd leave a sign?
叫安德森来
Get Anderson!
帮帮我们
亚麻油
Linseed oil.
没什么用  不能帮我们找到绑匪
Not much use, it doesn't lead us to the kidnapper.
很不错  安德森
Brilliant, Anderson.
- 是吗  - 是啊  很不错地展现了白痴的风范
- Really? - Yes, brilliant impression of an idiot.
看地板
Floor.
他为我们留下了足迹
He... made a trail for us.
男孩被逼着走在他们前面
The boy was made to walk ahead of them.
怎么  因为踮脚了吗
On what, tiptoe?
不安的表现
Indicates anxiety.
有人拿枪指着他的脑袋
Gun held to his head.
女孩被人拉着侧身走在他旁边
The girl was pulled beside him, dragged sideways.
他的胳膊架在她的脖子上
He had his left arm cradled about her neck.
就到这了  我们不知道他们接下来去哪了
That's the end of it, we don't know where they went from here.
到底还是没什么用
Tells us nothing after all.
说得对  安德森  是没什么用
You're right, Anderson, nothing.
只让我们知道他的鞋码  身高  步法和步速
Except his shoe size, his height, his gait, his walking pace.
玩得开心吗
Having fun?
现在开心了
Starting to.
或许还是别笑的好  毕竟有小孩被绑了
Maybe don't do the smiling. Kidnapped children?
如果门都锁上了  他怎么躲过的监视器
How could he get past the CCTV? If all the doors were locked.
他门没锁的时候就进来了
He walked in when they weren't locked.
但那种学校哪会让陌生人随意进出
But a stranger can't just walk into a school like that.
只要时机对  任何人都能随意进出任何地方
Anyone can walk in anywhere if they pick the right moment.
昨天是期末
Yesterday, end of term,
到处是家长  司机  员工
parents milling around, chauffeurs, staff.
他们中间再混进个陌生人谁会察觉
What's one more stranger among that lot?
他伺机行事
He was waiting for them.
只要找个好地方藏身即可
All he had to do was find a place to hide.
圣巴塞洛缪医院
茉莉
Molly!
你好啊  我正要出去
Hello, I'm just going out.
- 不  你不出去  - 我午饭约了人
- No, you're not. - I've got a lunch date.
- 取消吧  我们一起吃午餐  - 啥
- Cancel it, you're having lunch with me. - What?
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
事关你的一个前男友  我们正在追查他的下落
It's one of your old boyfriends, we're trying to track him down.
他近来有些捣蛋
He's been a bit naughty.
- 是莫里亚蒂干的吗  - 当然是他
- It's Moriarty? - Of course it's Moriarty!
其实金算不上是我男朋友
Jim actually wasn't even my boyfriend,
我们只约会过三次  我没再和他交往了
we went out three times. I ended it.
是啊  然后他去偷走了王冠和权杖
Yes, then he stole the Crown Jewels,
闯进英国央行
broke into the Bank of England
还组织了本顿维尔监狱的越狱
and organised a prison break in Pentonville.
为了维护法纪和秩序  我建议你
For the sake of law and order, I suggest you
将来就不要找男朋友了  茉莉
avoid all future attempts at a relationship, Molly.
那些油渍  约翰  绑匪脚印里的油渍
Oil, John. The oil in the kidnapper's footprint.
会帮我们找到莫里亚蒂
It'll lead us to Moriarty.
他鞋上所有的化学品都保存了下来
All the chemical traces on his shoe have been preserved.
鞋底就好像护照
The sole of the shoe is like a passport.
如果我们走运  能查到他最近的全部行踪
If we're lucky, we'll see everything he's been up to.
那个需要做分析
I need that analysis.
是碱性的
Alkaline.
- 谢谢你  约翰  - 是茉莉
- Thank you, John. - Molly.
是啊
Yes.
白垩
沥青
砖尘
植物
我欠你的
I... o... u.
甘油分子
Glycerol molecule.
甘油
甘油  丙烷  1,2,3  三醇  3羟基官能团
是什么东西
What are you?
你说"我欠你的"是什么意思
What did you mean, IOU?
你刚刚说"我欠你的"
You said IOU.
你刚刚一直在念叨这几个字
You were muttering it while you were working.
没什么  记下来的东西罢了
Nothing, mental note.
你有点像我爸  他死了  哦不  抱歉
You're a bit like my dad. He's dead. No, sorry.
茉莉  请不要觉得非得跟我搭讪
Molly, please don't feel the need to make conversation,
这真不是你的强项
it's really not your area.
他死前那段日子  总是很开心  心情愉悦
When he was dying, he was always cheerful, he was lovely,
可他以为没人看到他时就不是这样了
except when he thought no- one could see.
- 我有次看到他的样子  很哀伤  - 茉莉
- I saw him once, he looked sad. - Molly.
你就很哀伤  当你以为他看不到你的时候
You look sad, when you think he can't see you.
你没事吧  别说你没事
Are you OK? And don't just say you are,
因为我知道那种表情的含义
because I know what that means,
以为没人看着你时就流露哀伤的含义
looking sad when you think no- one can see you.
- 你就能看见我  - 我对你不算数
- You can see me. - I don't count.
我只是想说  如果我能做什么
What I'm trying to say is, that if there's anything I can do,
你需要我做任何事  我都会帮你
anything you need, anything at all, you can have me.
不是  我就是说  我是说
No, I just mean, I mean,
如果你需要我做什么事  我都可以
if there's anything you need, it's fine.
但我会需要你做什么
But what can I need from you?
没什么  我不知道
Nothing. I don't know.
其实你大可只说句谢谢
You could probably say thank you, actually.
那谢谢了
Thank you?
我要去买点薯片吃
I'm just going to go and get some crisps.
你想吃什么吗
Do you want anything?
算了  我知道你不吃
It's OK, I know you don't.
- 其实  要不我...  - 我知道你不吃
- Well, actually, maybe I'll... - I know you don't.
夏洛克
Sherlock?
箱子里的那个信封
This envelope that was in her trunk,
- 还有一个  - 什么
- there's another one. - What?
今天有人放在我们门阶上  没错  你瞧啊
On our doorstep. Found it today. Yes, and look at that.
你瞧  是完全相同的封印
Look at that, exactly the same seal.
- 面包屑  - 我回来的时候就放在那儿
- Breadcrumbs. - It was there when I got back.
面包屑留下的行迹
A little trace of breadcrumbs.
那本精装童话书
Hardback copy of Fairy Tales.
格林童话
两个孩子被邪恶的父亲领进了林子
Two children led into the forest by a wicked father,
他们跟着面包屑走
follow a little trail of breadcrumbs.
糖果屋
是《糖果屋》的故事
That's Hansel and Gretel.
什么样的绑匪还留下线索
What sort of kidnapper leaves clues?
喜欢自吹自擂的绑匪
The sort that likes to boast,
他把这一切看作是个游戏
the sort that thinks it's all a game.
他坐在我们的公寓里  对我说的原话是
He sat in our flat and he said these exact words to me...
每个童话故事都要有个老派的坏蛋
"All fairy tales need a good old- fashioned villain."
第五样物质  是童话的一部分
The fifth substance, it's part of the tale.
- 女巫的房子  - 啥
- The witch's house. - What?
甘油分子
The glycerol molecule.
聚甘油蓖麻醇酯
是聚甘油蓖麻醇酯
PGPR!
- 那是什么  - 是用来做巧克力的
- What's that? - It's used in making chocolate.
这是一小时前传真过来的
This fax arrived an hour ago.
快点啊
他们要死了
你查到了什么
What have you got for us?
我们要找出城里的一个地方
We need to find a place in the city
这五样东西在那里有交集
where all five of these things intersect.
白垩  沥青  砖尘  植物
Chalk, asphalt, brick dust, vegetation.
这是什么  巧克力
What is this? Chocolate?!
我认为我们要找的是一间废弃的糖果厂
I think we're looking for a disused sweet factory.
我们得缩小范围  有沥青的糖果厂呢
We need to narrow that down. A sweet factory with asphalt?
不行  还是太泛泛  得有更具体的东西
No, no, no, no, too general. Something more specific.
白垩  白垩质粘土  这样能缩小地理范围
Chalk, chalky clay. That's a far thinner band of geology.
砖尘
Brick dust?
建筑工地  五十年代的砖头
Building site. Bricks from the 1950s.
伦敦有几千个建筑工地
There's thousands of building sites in London.
- 我派人出去找了  - 我也有
- I've got people out looking. - So have I!
流浪汉的信息网  比警方敏捷多了
Homeless network, faster than the police,
也不介意收受贿赂
far more relaxed about taking bribes.
约翰
John.
彭土杜鹃  符合要求
Rhododendron ponticum. Matches.
白垩
砖尘
植物
巧克力
阿德斯顿
- 阿德斯顿  - 啥
- Addlestone. - What?
距离河和公园一英里的地方
There's a mile of disused factories
有处废弃厂房  符合所有要求
between the river and the park, it matches everything.
好吧  行动  行动
Right, come on. Come on!
好了  你们去那边看
OK, you look over there.
不要有疏漏
Look everywhere.
大家请散开  散开
OK, spread out, please, spread out.
刚刚熄灭的  他们还在这儿
This was alight moments ago. They're still here!
糖纸
Sweet wrappers?
他给你们吃什么了  汉塞尔和格莱特
What's he been feeding you? Hansel and Gretel.
- 水银  - 什么
- Mercury. - What?
糖纸  上面涂了水银  是有毒的
The papers, they're painted with mercury, lethal.
他们吃得越多
The more they ate...
就会要了他们的命
It was killing them.
但是单个不足以致命
But it's not enough to kill them on its own.
如果摄入足够多的量  最终会导致他们死亡
Taken in large enough quantities, eventually it would kill them.
他不需要亲自来行刑
He didn't need to be there for the execution.
遥控杀人  他可以待在千里之外
Murder by remote control, he could be 1,000 miles away.
他们越饿  吃得越多
The hungrier they got, the more they ate,
就死得越快  真漂亮
the faster they died. Neat.
- 控制一下  - 在这边
- Sherlock. - Over here!
我会照顾他  别担心
I've got him, don't worry.
好了  专业人士都问完了
Right then, the professionals are finished.
要是外行还想进去自己问问
If the amateurs want to go in and have their turn.
记住  她受了惊吓  而且只有七岁
Now remember, she's in shock and she's just seven years old,
所以  如果你能...
so, anything you can do to...
- 别太夏洛克吗  - 对  可能会比较好
- Not be myself? - Yeah, might be helpful.
克劳黛  我
Claudette, I...
别这样  我知道你很害怕
No, no, I know it's been hard for you.
- 克劳黛  听着  - 出去  出去
- Claudette, listen to me. - Out. Get out!
- 这没道理啊  - 孩子受惊过度
- Makes no sense. - Kid's traumatised.
夏洛克某些地方让她想起那个绑匪
Something about Sherlock reminds her of the kidnapper.
她说什么了吗
What's she said?
一个字都没说
Hasn't uttered another syllable.
- 那个男孩呢  - 还是昏迷不醒
- And the boy? - No, he's unconscious.
仍在重症监护中
He's still in intensive care.
别往心里去
Well, don't let it get to you,
每次看你进门  我都想尖叫
I always feel like screaming when you walk into a room.
说实话很多人都有同感
In fact, so do most people.
走吧
Come on.
只凭脚印你就找到了那些孩子  了不起
Brilliant work you did finding those kids from just a footprint,
真是太神奇了
it's really amazing.
谢谢
Thank you.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
- 你还好吗  - 在思考
- You OK? - Thinking.
我坐这辆  你等下辆吧
This is my cab, you get the next one.
- 为什么  - 你会说话
- Why? - You might talk.
"这是巧克力吗"
'Is this chocolate?'
"我们要找的是一家废弃的糖果厂"
'We're looking for a disused sweet factory.'
"出去"
'Get out!'
有问题吗
Problem?
伦敦出租车购物广告
This stunning evening wear
为您呈现这套华美的晚装配件
set from us here at London Taxi Shopping.
请把它关掉好吗
Can you turn this off, please?
如您所见  这套配件包括一副美丽的...
As you can see, the set comprises of a beautiful...
把这关掉行不行
Can you turn this off?!
搭配四条镶嵌式钻石手链
Accompanied by four spangly diamond bracelets...
你好
Hello.
准备好听故事了吗
Are you ready for the story?
这是自夸骑士的故事
This is the story of Sir Boast- a- lot.
一个脚印  这就是他所有的线索
A footprint, it's all he had.
一个脚印
A footprint.
是啊  你也知道他的能耐
Yeah, well, you know what he's like.
贝克街犯罪现场调查专家
CSI Baker Street.
可我们的人就做不到
Well, our boys couldn't have done it.
所以我们需要他  他更厉害
Well, that's why we need him, he's better.
这只是一种解释
That's one explanation.
还有别的解释吗
And what's the other?
自夸骑士是圆桌骑士中
Sir Boast- a- lot was the bravest
最勇敢  也是最聪明的骑士
and cleverest knight at the round table.
但其他骑士逐渐开始厌倦他那些
But soon the other knights began to grow tired of his stories
讲述他多么英勇
about how brave he was
颂扬他屠龙伟业的故事
and how many dragons he'd slain.
很快他们就开始怀疑
And soon they began to wonder,
自夸爵士的故事究竟是不是真的
"Are Sir Boast- a- lot's stories even true?"
只有他能找到那些证据
Only he could have found that evidence.
不  不
No. No
那女孩看到他时  叫得撕心裂肺
The girl screams her head off when she sees him...
她可从来没见过他
A man she has never seen before,
除非她以前见过他
unless she had seen him before.
你究竟想说什么
What's your point?
你知道我想说什么  你只是不想相信
You know what it is, you just don't want to think about it.
于是所有的骑士都去对亚瑟王说
So, all of the knights went to King Arthur and said,
"我不相信自夸骑士的故事"
'I don't believe Sir Boast- a- lot's stories.'
"他就是个大骗子"
'He's just a big old liar'
"都是他编的故事  让自己显得很了不起"
'who makes things up to make himself look good.
你们不会真以为是他干的吧
You're not seriously suggesting he's involved, are you?
我认为我们得考虑这种可能性
I think we have to entertain the possibility.
后来  甚至连国王也开始怀疑
And then, even the King began to wonder.
但自夸骑士的最终问题还不是这个
But that wasn't the end of Sir Boast- a- lot's problem.
不
No.
这还不是他的最终问题
That wasn't the final problem.
故事讲完了
The end.
停车
Stop the cab.
Stop the cab!
那是怎么回事
What was that?!
那是什么
What was that?
不要钱了
No charge.
小心
Watch out!
谢谢
Thank you.
夏洛克
Sherlock!
是他  是那个人
That is him. It's him.
叫苏莱曼尼什么的
Sulejmani or something,
麦考夫给我看过他的档案
Mycroft showed me his file.
他是阿尔巴尼亚的黑帮大佬
He's a big Albanian gangster,
住的地方跟我们只隔两户
lives two doors down from us.
- 他因为跟我握手而被杀  - 什么意思
- He died because I shook his hand. - What do you mean?
他救了我的命  却不能碰我  为什么
He saved my life, but he couldn't touch me. Why?
我们家门口就住着四个杀手
Four assassins living right on our doorstep.
他们不是来杀我的
They haven't come here to kill me.
他们必须保住我的命
They have to keep me alive.
我手上有他们都想要的东西
I've got something that all of them want.
但如果他们中任何一个接近我
But if one of them approaches me,
其他人就会杀死他
The others kill them before they can get it.
选择您要使用的网络
从以下列表中选择您要使用的网络 必要时请输入网络密码
所有注意力都在我身上
All of the attention is focused on me.
一张严密的监控网正监视着我们
There's a surveillance web closing in on us right now.
你手上究竟有什么东西这么重要
So what have you got that's so important?
我得问问除尘的状况
I need to ask about the dusting.
要精确的细节  上个星期哪里被清扫过
Precise details, in the last week, what's been cleaned?
星期二  我清理了你的地毯
Tuesday, I did your lino.
不  是这里  我们要在这个房间找
No, in here, this room, this is where we'll find it.
任何灰尘被擦拭的痕迹
Any break in the dust line.
什么都能归位  但灰尘不行
You can put back anything but dust.
灰尘即铁证
Dust is eloquent.
他这是要做什么
What is it all about?
找摄像头  我们被监视了
Cameras, we're being watched.
什么  摄像头  在这儿吗
What?! Cameras? Here?
我穿着睡衣呢
I'm in my nightie!
- 不  探长  - 怎么了
- No, Inspector. - Why?
- 我的回答是不  - 我什么都没问呢
- The answer's no. - You've not heard the question!
你想把我带到警署去
You want to take me to the station.
就不麻烦你开口问了
Just saving you the trouble of asking.
夏洛克
Sherlock.
- 因为那声尖叫  - 是的
- The scream? - Yeah.
是谁说的  多诺万  肯定是多诺万
Who was it? Donovan? I bet it was Donovan.
我是否与绑架案有牵连
"Am I somehow responsible for the kidnapping?"
莫里亚蒂很聪明
Moriarty is smart.
他在她脑海里植入怀疑的种子
He planted that doubt in her head.
那种感觉萦绕不去
That little nagging sensation.
很难抗拒
You're going to have to be strong to resist.
你没法扼杀一种想法  对吧
You can't kill an idea, can you?
只要它在这里  生根发芽
Not once it's made a home... there.
你会跟我走吗
Will you come?
他的下一步棋  是一张照片
One photograph, that's his next move.
莫里亚蒂的游戏
Moriarty's game.
先是孩子的尖叫
First the scream,
然后是我被带去问讯的照片
then a photograph of me being taken in for questioning.
他想一点一点地毁了我
He wants to destroy me inch by inch.
这是一场游戏  雷斯垂德
It is a game, Lestrade,
而我并不想参与
and not one I'm willing to play.
代我向多诺万警佐问好
Give my regards to Sergeant Donovan.
- 他们会作出决定  - 什么决定
- They'll be deciding. - Deciding?
是否带着逮捕令回来逮捕我
Whether to come back with a warrant and arrest me.
你这么觉得吗
You think?
这是标准程序
Standard procedure.
你应该跟他走  别人会以为...
You should have gone with him. People'll think...
我才不在乎别人怎么想
I don't care what people think.
但你不想让他们认为你很蠢  或犯了错
You'd care if they thought you were stupid or wrong.
不  是他们蠢  他们犯了错
No, that would just make them stupid or wrong.
夏洛克  我不想让这个世界以为你是...
Sherlock, I don't want the world believing you're...
以为我是什么
That I am what?
骗子
A fraud.
- 你担心他们是对的  - 什么
- You're worried they're right. - What?
- 你担心他们对我的判断是对的  - 不
- That they're right about me. - No.
这就是你烦躁的原因
That's why you're upset.
你不能不考虑  他们或许是对的
You can't entertain the possibility they may be right.
- 你害怕自己也受了骗  - 我没有
- You're afraid you've been taken in as well. - No, no.
莫里亚蒂也在玩弄你的思想
Moriarty is playing with your mind, too.
你难道看不出是怎么回事吗
Can't you SEE what's going on?!
不  我认识的是真实的你
No, I know you for real.
百分之百吗
100 percent?
谁会一直假装成这么个讨厌鬼
Well, nobody could fake being such an annoying dick all the time.
- 夏洛克・福尔摩斯  - 是的  长官
- Sherlock Holmes? - Yes, sir.
媒体上经常报道的那个家伙
That bloke that's been in the press?
我以为他是个私家侦探
I thought he was some sort of private eye.
- 他是的  - 我们一直都在向他咨询
- He is. - We've been consulting with him,
你是这个意思吗
that's what you're telling me?
我们没有让他插手过机要案件吧
Not used him on any proper cases though, have we?
有那么一两个吧
Well, one or two.
或许是二三十个
Or 20 or 30.
什么
What?!
不是只有我这么做  格雷格森...
I'm not the only senior officer who did this. Gregson...
闭嘴
Shut up!
一个业余侦探
An amateur detective
居然能接触到各种机密信息
given access to all sorts of classified information.
现在他还是一个案件的疑犯
And now he's a suspect in a case.
- 恕我直言  - 你这个白痴  雷斯垂德
- With all due respect... - You're a bloody idiot, Lestrade!
现在就去把他抓来  就现在
Now go and fetch him in, right now.
去抓他
Do it!
现在你们得意了
Proud of yourselves?
要是不止这一个案子呢
Well, what if it's not just this case?
要是每次他都是在耍我们呢
What if he's done this to us every single time?
警局里还是有人护着我们的  是雷斯垂德
So, still got some friends on the force. It's Lestrade.
他说他们正赶过来
Says they're all coming over here now.
所有被你弄得没面子的警官
Queuing up to slap on the handcuffs.
都排着队要来拷你呢
Every officer you've ever made feel like a tit,
那可是不少人呢
which is a lot of people.
抱歉  是不是打扰你们了
Sorry, am I interrupting?
有人送来一个包裹  我给忘了
Some chap delivered a parcel, I forgot,
上面标记说易腐烂
marked perishable.
我只好签收了
I had to sign for it.
名字挺滑稽  是德语  像是童话里的
Funny name, German, like the fairy tales.
烧焦了
Burnt to a crisp.
这是什么意思
What does it mean?
- 警察  - 我去开门
- Police! - I'll go.
夏洛克
Sherlock.
- 抱歉  赫德森太太  - 我们得谈谈
- Excuse me, Mrs Hudson. - We need to talk to you.
别就这么闯进来呀
Don't barge in like that!
你们有逮捕令吗  有吗
Have you got a warrant? Have you?
别插手  约翰
Leave it, John.
讲点礼貌
Manners!
夏洛克・福尔摩斯  我现在
Sherlock Holmes, I'm arresting you
以涉嫌诱拐和绑架的罪名逮捕你
on suspicion of abduction and kidnapping.
- 没关系  约翰  - 他没有反抗
- It's OK, John. He's not resisting...
不  这怎么会没关系  这太荒谬了
No, it's not all right, this is ridiculous.
现在带他下楼
Get him downstairs now.
你真不该这么做
You really don't have to do this.
别妨碍公务  不然我连你一起逮捕
Don't try to interfere or I shall arrest you too.
你满意了吗
You done?
我早就说过
I said it.
- 我们初次见面的时候  - 算了吧
- First time we met. - Don't bother.
他不会满足于破案
Solving crimes won't be enough.
总有一天  他会越过底线
One day he'll cross the line.
你自己想想  什么人会去绑架孩子
Now ask yourself, what sort of man would kidnap those kids
就为了通过找回他们来显摆自己
just so he can impress us all by finding them?
- 多诺万  - 长官
- Donovan? - Sir?
- 人抓住了吗  - 是的  长官
- Got our man? - Yes, sir.
要我说的话  看着他就觉得古怪
Looked a bit of a weirdo, if you ask me.
这种义警通常都这样
Often are, these vigilante types.
你看什么呢
What are you looking at?
你还好吗  长官
Are you all right, sir?
- 来跟我作伴了  - 是的
- Joining me? - Yeah.
显然打总警司一拳
Well, apparently it's against the law
属于违法行为
to chin the Chief Superintendent.
这可不太聪明
Bit awkward this.
这下没人来保释我们了
There's no- one to bail us.
我更倾向于现在就大胆逃跑
I was thinking more about our imminent and daring escape.
- 所有单位到27区  - 什么
- All units to 27. - What?
所有单位到2
All units to 2...
女士们  先生们  请你们趴下好吗
Ladies and gentlemen, will you all please get on your knees?
- 最好现在就趴下  - 照他说的做
- NOW would be good! - Do as he says!
提醒你们一声  枪是他夺的
Just so you're aware, the gun is his idea,
我就是个  你知道
I'm just a... you know.
我的人质
My hostage.
人质  没错  这个可以有
Hostage, yes, that works.
这个可以有
That works.
现在怎么办
So what now?
如莫里亚蒂所愿  做个逃犯  跑
Doing what Moriarty wants, becoming a fugitive. Run!
追上他  雷斯垂德
Get after him, Lestrade!
抓紧我的手
Take my hand.
这下肯定要被人闲话了
Now people will definitely talk.
- 枪掉了  - 别管了
- The gun! - Leave it!
夏洛克  等等
Sherlock, wait!
我们得协调一致才行
We're going to need to coordinate.
往右边去  往你右边去
Go to your right. Go to your right.
每个人都宁可信其有
Everybody wants to believe it,
这就是其高明之处
that's what makes it so clever.
一个比真相更受人青睐的谎言
A lie that's preferable to the truth.
我的演绎法是骗人的
My deductions were a sham.
大家都舒坦了  夏洛克毫无过人之处
No- one feels inadequate, Sherlock's an ordinary man.
麦考夫  他能帮我们
Mycroft, he could help us.
现在真不是打亲情牌的好时机
Big family reconciliation, now's not really the moment.
夏洛克
Sherlock...
有人跟来了
we're being followed.
我就知道躲不过警察
I knew we couldn't outrun the police.
那人不是警察
That's not the police,
是咱们贝克街上的新邻居
it's one of my new neighbours from Baker Street.
看他能不能给我们答案
Let's see if he can give us some answers.
我们去哪儿
Where are we going?
我们要冲到那辆巴士前面
We're going to jump in front of that bus.
你想从我这里得到什么
Tell me what you want from me.
告诉我
Tell me!
他放在你公寓里了
He left it at your flat.
- 谁  - 莫里亚蒂
- Who? - Moriarty.
放了什么
What?
- 程序代码  - 这就对了
- The computer key code. - Of course.
他公开售卖
He's selling it.
闯进伦敦塔的程序
The programme he used to break into the Tower.
他是在来的时候动的手脚
He planted it when he came around.
它可以扭转局面
It's a game- changer.
它是把钥匙  能攻破任何系统
It's a key, it can break into any system
此时此刻就在我们公寓
and it's sitting in our flat right now.
所以他留下那个信息
That's why he left that message,
告诉大家该去哪里  "去找夏洛克"
telling everyone where to come, "Get Sherlock!"
我们必须回公寓找到它
We need to get back into the flat and search.
刑事调查局在那守着
CID will be camped out.
为什么栽赃给你
Why plant it on you?
又一个搞坏我名声的歪点子
It's another subtle way of smearing my name,
现在我成了那些罪行的最大嫌疑人
now I'm best pals with all those criminals.
你看过这个吗
Yeah, well, have you seen this?
大爆料
A kiss- and- tell.
夏洛克  骇人听闻的真相
密友理查・布鲁克彻底坦白
一个叫理查・布鲁克的家伙
Some bloke called Rich Brook.
这人是谁
Who is he?
现在发表声明是不是太晚了
Too late to go on the record?
恭喜了  "夏洛克・福尔摩斯的真相"
Congratulations, "The Truth About Sherlock Holmes."
谁都想要的独家  而你搞到了  漂亮
The scoop that everybody wanted and you got it. Bravo!
我给过你机会
I gave you your opportunity.
我本想站在你这边  记得吗
I wanted to be on your side, remember?
你拒绝了我  所以...
You turned me down, so...
然后就有大惊喜  有人爆出猛料
Then lo and behold, someone spills all the beans.
真是心想事成  布鲁克是谁
How utterly convenient. Who is Brook?
说吧  姬蒂  鬼才相信电话爆料
Come on, Kitty, no- one trusts the voice at the end of a phone.
毫无疑问  咖啡馆里碰面
All those little meetings in cafes,
酒店房间里会谈
those sessions in the hotel room
他对着采访机侃侃而谈
when he gabbled into your Dictaphone.
你怎么就相信他了呢
How do you know that you can trust him?
一个揣着圣杯冒出来的家伙
A man turns up with the Holy Grail in his pockets.
他怎么让你信服的呢
What were his credentials?
亲爱的  买不到咖啡粉煮的
Darling, they didn't have any ground coffee,
我就买了普通的
so I just got normal.
你说过他们不可能找到这里来
You said that they wouldn't find me here,
你说过我在这里很安全
you said that I'd be safe here.
你很安全
You are safe.
理查  我是证人
Richard, I'm a witness,
他们不会当着证人的面伤害你
they wouldn't harm you in front of witnesses.
这就是你的爆料人
So that's your source?
莫里亚蒂就是理查・布鲁克
Moriarty is Richard Brook?
他就是理查・布鲁克  不存在莫里亚蒂
Of course he's Richard Brook, there is no Moriarty.
从来就没有这个人
There never has been.
- 你说什么胡话  - 仔细看看他
- What are you talking about? - Look him up.
理查・布鲁克  夏洛克雇来扮演莫里亚蒂的人
Rich Brook, an actor Sherlock Holmes hired to be Moriarty.
华生医生  我知道你是好人
Dr Watson, I know you're a good man,
不要  不要伤害我
don't, don't, don't hurt me.
不对  你是莫里亚蒂  他就是莫里亚蒂
No, you are Moriarty! He's Moriarty!
我们见过  记得吗  你想把我炸死
We've met, remember? You were going to blow me up!
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
他出钱雇我  而我需要活儿
He paid me, I needed the work.
我是个演员  我失业了
I'm an actor, I was out of work.
夏洛克  你最好解释一下
Sherlock, you'd better explain,
我完全搞不懂了
because I am not getting this.
我来解释吧  白纸黑字
I'll be doing the explaining, in print.
全在这里  板上钉钉的证据
It's all here, conclusive proof.
夏洛克是个骗子
他策划了所有的罪案
你虚构出金姆斯・莫里亚蒂  所谓的夙敌
You invented James Moriarty, your nemesis.
虚构出来的
Invented him?!
事实上所有的罪案都是他策划的
He invented all the crimes, actually.
最厉害的是凭空造出一位犯罪大师
And to cap it all, he made up a master villain.
- 这太扯了  - 问他啊
- Don't be ridiculous! - Ask him.
他就在这里  问他啊
He's right here. Just ask him.
- 告诉他  理查  - 得了吧  他上过庭
- Tell him, Richard. - For God's sake, this man was on trial!
没错  就是你付钱让他背黑锅
Yes, and you paid him, pay him to take the rap.
还保证搞定陪审团
Promised you'd rig the jury.
虽然不是伦敦西区的角色  但我猜钱也不少
Not exactly a West End role, but I'll bet the money was good.
但也不够多  否则他不会爆料
But not so good he didn't want to sell his story.
对不起  诚心的  非常抱歉
I am sorry. I am. I am sorry.
你准备发表的就是这个故事
So this is the story you're going to publish?
最后的结论就是
The big conclusion of it all,
莫里亚蒂只是个演员
Moriarty's an actor?
他心里明白
He knows I am.
我有证据  有证据  给他们看...
I have proof. I have proof. Show them...
姬蒂  给他们看看
Kitty, show them something.
好啊  拿出来我看看
Yeah, show me something.
我上过电视  是儿童频道
I'm on TV. I'm on kids' TV.
我讲故事
I'm the story- teller.
理查・布鲁克
获奖演员参演热门医疗剧
我讲故事  出过DVD
I'm the story- teller. It's on DVD.
理查・布鲁克
简历
告诉他
Just tell him.
反正都这样了  不用瞒了
It's all coming out. It's all over.
告诉他们  说啊  说啊  还瞒什么啊
Just tell them. Just tell them. Tell them! It's all over now!
不要  别碰我  你休想碰我
No! Don't you touch me! Don't you lay a finger on me!
你耍够了吧
Stop it now!
别伤害我  不要让他过来
Don't hurt me! Don't let him get away!
放过他
Leave him alone!
不行不行  他还有后援
No, no, no. He'll have back- up.
你知道吗  夏洛克・福尔摩斯
Do you know what, Sherlock Holmes?
我现在算是看透你了  你让我恶心
I look at you know and I can read you... and you repel me.
他真能做到吗
Can he do that?
彻底改变身份  把你抹黑成罪犯
Completely change his identity, make you the criminal?
他彻底掌握了我的情况
He's got my whole life story.
要想兜售一个天大的谎言
That's what you do when you sell a big lie,
将其包裹在真相之中  看上去无懈可击
you wrap it up in the truth to make it more palatable.
这只是你的一家之言了
It'll be your word against his.
他用一天时间在人们脑袋里埋下怀疑的种子
He's been sowing doubt into people's minds for 24 hours.
再做一件事
There's only one thing
就能结束这场游戏  那就是...
he needs to do to complete his game and that...
夏洛克
Sherlock?
我要去做一件事
There's something I need to do.
- 什么事  我能帮忙吗  - 不  我得一个人干
- What? Can I help? - No, on my own.
你之前说错了  知道吗
You're wrong, you know?
你的确算数
You do count.
你一直都算数  我始终相信你
You've always counted and I've always trusted you.
但你也说对了
But you were right.
我的确有事
I'm not OK.
你怎么了
Tell me what's wrong.
茉莉  我可能快死了
Molly, I think I'm going to die.
你需要什么
What do you need?
如果我不是你所以为的样子
If I wasn't everything that you think I am,
甚至不是我所以为的样子
everything that I think I am...
你还愿意帮我吗
would you still want to help me?
你需要什么
What do you need?
你
You.
她真的做了不少功课  那个莱利小姐
She has really done her homework, Miss Riley,
这些事只有和夏洛克最亲近的人才知道
and it's things that only someone close to Sherlock could know.
你最近有没有看过你弟弟的通讯录
Have you seen your brother's address book lately?
只有两个名字  你跟我
Two names... yours and mine...
而莫里亚蒂不是从我这里得到的
and Moriarty didn't get this stuff from me.
- 约翰  - 怎么回事  你们什么关系
- John... - So how does it work, your relationship?
你们是不是偶尔出去喝喝咖啡  你跟金
Do you go out for a coffee now and then, you and Jim?
你的亲弟弟
Your own brother
你把他的生平故事都告诉了这个疯子
and you blabbed about his entire life to this maniac.
我根本没打算...我根本没想过...
I never intend... I never dreamt...
你当时就是想跟我说这件事吧
This... this is what you were trying to tell me, isn't it?
"照看好他  因为我犯了个错"
"Watch his back because I've made a mistake."
你怎么认识他的
How did you meet him?
他这样的人  我们很了解  尽在掌控之中
People like him, we know about them, we watch them.
但是金姆斯・莫里亚蒂
But James Moriarty...
拥有前所未有的犯罪头脑
the most dangerous criminal mind the world has ever seen,
以及最终极的武器
and, in his pocket, the ultimate weapon.
程序代码
The key code.
区区几行程序就能畅通无阻
A few lines of computer code that can unlock any door.
你绑架他就是为了套出代码
And you abducted him to try and find the key code?
我们对他审问了数周
Interrogated him for weeks.
- 结果呢  - 他不合作
- And? - He wouldn't play along.
他只是坐着
He just sat there
凝视着黑暗
staring into the darkness.
唯一能让他开口的是...
The only thing that made him open up...
我可以让他说话  就一点点
I could get him to talk, just a little.
可是...
But...
作为回报  你把夏洛克的故事透露给他
In return you had to offer him Sherlock's life story.
所以  这个天大的谎言
So, one big lie...
夏洛克是个骗子
Sherlock's a fraud,
人们会相信  因为别的部分都是真的
and people will swallow it because the rest of it's true.
莫里亚蒂想要毁了夏洛克
Moriarty wanted Sherlock destroyed, right,
而你给他送去了最强力的武器
and you have given him the perfect ammunition.
约翰
John.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
算了吧
Please!
转告他  好吗
Tell him, would you?
我收到你的短信
I got your message.
程序代码是问题的关键
The computer code is the key to this.
把它找出来并加以使用
We find it, we can use it.
用莫里亚蒂的方式击败他
Beat Moriarty in his own game.
你说使用是什么意思
What do you mean use it?
他用来编造了一个假身份
He used it to create a false identity
我们也能篡改记录  销毁理查・布鲁克
so we can break into the records and destroy Richard Brook.
把金・莫里亚蒂逼回来
Bring back Jim Moriarty again.
他无罪释放那天
Somewhere in 221b,
他把代码藏在了221B的某个地方
somewhere on the day of the verdict he left it hidden.
- 他碰过什么  - 一个苹果  仅此而已
- What did he touch? - An apple, nothing else.
- 他写了什么吗  - 没有
- Did he write anything down? - No.
\h过来玩吧
\h\h\h巴茨医院楼顶
夏・福
顺便
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h带了你也许想拿回去的东西
是我  请讲
Yeah, speaking.
什么
What?
怎么了  她没事吧
What happened? Is she OK?
不是吧  好  我这就来
My God! Right, yes, I'm coming.
- 什么事  - 是医护人员
- What is it? - Paramedics.
赫德森太太受到了枪击
Mrs Hudson's been shot.
怎么回事
What? How?
没准是你引来的那些杀手  天啊
Probably one of the killers you managed to attract. Jesus! Jesus!
她不行了  夏洛克  走吧
She's dying, Sherlock. Let's go.
你去  我很忙
You go. I'm busy.
- 忙  - 思考  我需要思考
- Busy?! - Thinking. I need to think.
你需要...你一点儿都不关心她吗
You need to...? Doesn't she mean anything to you?
上回有人碰了碰她  你就差点把他杀了
You once half- killed a man because he laid a finger on her.
- 她是我房东  - 她快死了
- She's my landlady. - She's dying...
你太冷血了
you machine!
活见鬼  你就留在这里吧  随你便
Sod this. Sod this! You stay here if you want, on your own.
我只有孤独作伴  孤独能保护我
Alone is what I have. Alone protects me.
不对  保护我们的是朋友
No, friends protect people.
\h\h\h我在等着你哦
金・莫
好了
Well...
终于见面了
here we are at last.
就我们俩  夏洛克
You and me, Sherlock.
我们的问题  终极问题
And our problem... the final problem.
活着
Staying alive!
无聊透顶吧
It's so boring, isn't it?
一成不变
It's just staying.
我这辈子都在找乐子
All my life I've been searching for distractions
你曾经那么有趣  现在也没意思了
and you were the best distraction and now I don't even have you
因为我打败了你
because I've beaten you.
你知道吗
And you know what?
说到底  太简单了
In the end, it was easy.
没劲
It was easy.
我只能回去找普通人玩了
Now I've got to go back to playing with the ordinary people,
而到头来  你也不过和他们一样是个普通人
and it turns out you're ordinary, just like all of them.
好吧
Well.
你是不是开始怀疑我是不是真的了
Did you almost start to wonder if I was real?
你是不是也被我耍了啊
Did I nearly get you?
理查・布鲁克
Richard Brook.
没人看出其中的亮点  但你看出来了
Nobody seems to get the joke, but you do.
- 当然了  - 真不错
- Of course. - Attaboy.
理查・布鲁克的德语就是莱辛巴赫
Richard Brook in German is Reichenbach.
- 那个让我出名的案子  - 只是觉得这样很好玩啦
- The case that made my name. - Just trying to have some fun.
不错啊  你这也看出来了
Good. You got that too.
数字一样的节奏
Beats like digits.
每一拍就是1  其余的都是0
Every beat is a one, every rest is a zero.
二进制代码
Binary code.
所以那些杀手都要救我
That's why all those assassins tried to save my life.
代码就藏在我身上  藏在我脑海里
It was hidden on me, hidden inside my head.
简单的几行程序代码
A few simple lines of computer code
就可以破解任何系统
that can break into any system.
我对那些客户说  最后一名是胆小鬼
Told all my clients, last one to Sherlock is a sissy.
但现在我都知道了  我能用这个修改记录
But now that it's up here, I can use it to alter all the records.
我能抹杀理查・布鲁克  弄回金・莫里亚蒂
I can kill Rich Brook and bring back Jim Moriarty.
不不不  这也太简单了
No, no, no, no, no. This is too easy.
太简单了
This is too easy.
根本就没什么代码  笨蛋
There is no key, doofus!
那些数字毫无意义  一点意义都没有
Those digits are meaningless. They're utterly meaningless.
你不会真以为几行程序代码
You don't really think a couple of lines of computer code
就能破解全世界的系统吗
are going to crash the world around our ears?
我好失望哦  普通人夏洛克
I'm disappointed in you, ordinary Sherlock.
- 但那个节奏  - 是巴赫的1号协奏曲  谢谢
- But the rhythm... Partita no 1! Thank you, Johann Sebastian Bach.
- 那你又是怎么...  - 怎么黑进银行
- But then how did you... ? - How did I break into the bank,
伦敦塔  还有监狱吗
to the Tower, to the prison?
光天化日下的抢劫  只要有同伙就行啦
Daylight robbery! All it takes is some willing participants.
好戏开始了哦
我知道你会上钩  这是你的弱点
I knew you'd fall for it. That's your weakness.
你总是把事情想得很聪明
You always want everything to be clever.
我们的游戏能结束了吗  最后一幕
Shall we finish the game? One final act.
幸好你选了一栋高楼  那样做效果很好
Glad you chose a tall building. Nice way to do it.
做  做什么
Do it? Do what?
是啊  当然了
Yes, of course.
自杀
My suicide.
天才侦探是个骗子
Genius detective proved to be a fraud.
我在报纸上看到  肯定是真的
I read it in the paper so it must be true.
我最爱报纸了
I love newspapers.
还有童话故事
Fairy tales.
尤其喜欢黑暗的童话
And pretty grim ones too.
天啊  约翰  你吓死我了  警察那边没事吧
God, John, you made me jump. Is everything OK with the police?
夏洛克都解决了吧
Has Sherlock sorted it all out?
我的天
My God.
出租车
Taxi!
出租车  等等  我是警察  算是吧
Taxi! No, no, no. Police... sort of!
谢了  伙计  太谢谢了
Thanks, mate. Thanks a lot!
我能证明你伪造了那个假身份
I can prove that you created an entirely false identity.
你就自杀吧  那样省力多了
Just kill yourself. It's a lot less effort.
跳啊
Go on.
为了我
For me.
好不好啦
Please!
你疯了
You're insane.
你刚刚知道吗
You're just getting that now? Wo- wo- wo!
好吧
Ok.
我再给你点动力
Let me give you a little extra incentive.
要是你不跳  你朋友就会死
Your friends will die if you don't.
- 约翰  - 不止是约翰  还有
- John? - Not just John. Everyone.
- 赫德森太太  - 还有
- Mrs Hudson? - Everyone.
- 雷斯垂德  - 三发子弹  三个杀手  三个死者
- Lestrade? - Three bullets, three gunmen, three victims.
没有人能阻止他们了
There's no stopping them now...
除非他们看到你跳楼
unless my people see you jump.
尽管逮捕我  折磨我好了
You can have me arrested, you can torture me,
你想拿我怎么样随便你
you can do anything you like with me,
但没什么能阻止他们扣下扳机
but nothing's going to prevent them from pulling the trigger.
你在这世上唯一的三个朋友死定了
Your only three friends in the world will die unless...
- 除非  - 我自杀  成就你的故事
- Unless... - I kill myself and complete your story.
你得承认  这样更吸引人
You've got to admit, that's sexier.
- 我声名狼藉地死去  - 当然了  这才是重点
- And I die in disgrace. - Of course. That's the point of this.
你现在有观众了哦
You've got an audience now.
请吧
Off you pop.
跳吧
Go on.
我告诉过你故事的结局
I told you how this ends.
只有你死
Your death is the only thing
杀手才会收手
that's going to call off the killers.
我肯定不会这么做
I'm certainly not going to do it.
你能给我点时间吗
Would you give me one moment, please?
让我一个人待会
One moment of privacy.
拜托了
Please.
当然可以
Of course.
什么
What?!
你笑什么
What is it?
你知道了什么
What did I miss?
你不会这么做
You're not going to do it.
所以还有办法让杀手收手
So the killers can be called off,
有个代码  暗号或数字
then there's a recall code or a word or a number.
如果我有你
I don't have to die
我就不用死
if I've got you.
你觉得你能让我下令让他们住手吗
You think you can make me stop the order?
- 你觉得你能做到吗  - 当然
- You think you can make me do that? - Yes.
- 你也这么觉得  - 夏洛克  你哥哥和整个政府的人
- So do you. - Sherlock, your big brother and all the King's horses
都不能逼我做我不想做的事
couldn't make me do a thing I didn't want to.
是的  但我不是我哥哥  记得吗
Yes, but I'm not my brother, remember?
我是你
I am you.
准备好做任何事
Prepared to do anything.
准备好毁灭一切
Prepared to burn.
准备好做普通人做不到的事
Prepared to do what ordinary people won't do.
你想和我在地狱里相见吗
You want me to shake hands with you in hell?
那我奉陪
I shall not disappoint you.
不
Nah.
你这话说大了
You talk big.
才不是呢
Nah.
你是普通人
You're ordinary.
你是普通人  你站在正义那一方
You're ordinary. You're on the side of the angels.
我也许是站在正义那一方
I may be on the side of the angels,
但这绝不代表我和他们是一种人
but don't think for one second that I am one of them.
对
No...
你不是
you're not.
我懂了
I see.
你不是普通人
You're not ordinary.
不是
No.
你是我
You're me.
你就是我
谢谢
Thank you...
夏洛克・福尔摩斯
Sherlock Holmes.
谢谢你了
Thank you.
上帝保佑你
Bless you.
只要我还活着
As long as I'm alive,
你就能救你的朋友  你就会有退路
you can save your friends, you've got a way out.
那就祝你好运了
Well, good luck with that.
不
No.
是的  先生  谢谢  再见
Yes, sir. Thank you. Bye.
喂
Hello?
- 约翰  - 夏洛克  你没事吧
- John. - Hey, Sherlock. Are you OK?
转过身  往回走  我这就来
Turn around and walk back the way you came. I'm coming in.
照我说的做
Just do as I ask!
求你了
Please.
在哪
Where?
停在那别动
Stop there.
- 夏洛克  - 好了  抬头  我在屋顶上
- Sherlock? - OK, look up. I'm on the rooftop.
天啊
God.
我不能下来  所以我们只能这么说话了
I... I can't come down, so we'll just have to do it like this.
怎么了
What's going on?
我要道歉
An apology.
这一切都是真的
It's all true.
什么
What?
他们说的关于我的一切  我创造了莫里亚蒂
Everything they said about me. I invented Moriarty.
你为什么要这么说
Why are you saying this?
我是个冒牌货
I'm a fake.
- 夏洛克  - 报纸上写的都是真的
- Sherlock... - The newspapers were right all along.
我要你告诉雷斯垂德
I want you to tell Lestrade,
告诉赫德森太太和茉莉
I want you to tell Mrs Hudson and Molly.
告诉所有相信你的人
In fact, tell anyone who will listen to you...
我为了自己创造了莫里亚蒂
that I created Moriarty for my own purposes.
好了  闭嘴  夏洛克  别说了
OK, shut up Sherlock. Shut up.
我们第一次见面的时候
The first time we met... the first time we met,
- 你就对我姐姐的事了如指掌吧  - 没人能这么聪明
- you knew all about my sister, right? - Nobody could be that clever.
你就可以
You could.
我调查了你
I researched you.
我们见面之前  我查了所有关于你的资料
Before we met, I discovered everything that I could
就为了让你印象深刻
to impress you.
这只是个把戏罢了
It's a trick. Just a magic trick.
不  快别说了
No. All right, stop it now.
不  站在那别动
No. Stay exactly where you are.
- 别动  - 好吧
- Don't move. - All right.
好好看着我
Keep your eyes fixed on me.
- 求你了  你能为我做这件事吗  - 什么事
- Please, will you do this for me? - Do what?
这通电话
This phone call, it's...
是我的遗言
it's my note.
人们都会这么做的吧
It's what people do, don't they?
留遗言
Leave a note?
留什么鬼遗言啊
Leave a note when?
- 再见  约翰  - 不  不要
- Goodbye, John. - No. Don't...
夏洛克
Sherlock!
Sherlock.
夏洛克
Sherlock... Sherlock.
我是医生  让我过去  快让我过去
I'm a doctor, let me come through. Let me come through, please.
他是我朋友  是我朋友  求求你们
He's my friend. He's my friend... Please.
求你们了  让我...
Please, let me just...
上帝啊
Jesus!
不
No.
这不是真的
God, no.
冒牌天才自杀
你有什么想说
There's stuff that you wanted to say...
- 却没有说的话  - 嗯
- but didn't say it. - Yeah.
现在说出来吧
Say it now.
对不起  我做不到
Sorry, I can't.
所有那些东西  那些科学仪器
There's all the stuff. All the science equipment.
我都装在盒子里了  不知道该怎么办
I left it all in boxes. I don't know what needs doing.
我觉得还是捐给学校吧
I thought I'd take it to a school.
你要不要...
Would you...?
我现在暂时没法回去  我要缓一缓
I can't go back to the flat again, not at the moment.
我好生气
I'm angry.
没事的  约翰  这没什么奇怪
It's OK, John. There's nothing unusual in that.
他让每个人都生气
That's the way he made everyone feel.
夏洛克・福尔摩斯
看他在我桌子上留下的记号  还有那些噪音
All the marks on my table and the noise,
- 在凌晨一点半开枪  - 是啊
- firing guns at half past one in the morning... - Yeah.
还把该死的标本放在我冰箱里
Bloody specimens in my fridge.
- 你怎么能在放吃的地方放尸体  - 是啊
- Imagine, keeping bodies where there's food. - Yes.
还打架  还把墙壁弄得乱七八糟
And the fighting! Drove me up the wall with all his carryings- on.
听着  我其实没有这么生气  好吗
Listen, I'm not actually that angry, OK?
好吧  我让你一个人待会
OK. I'll leave you alone to, you know...
你曾经对我说过
You... you told me once...
你不是个英雄
that you weren't a hero.
我也曾一度以为你不是人
There were times I didn't even think you were human,
但我要对你说  你是...
but let me tell you this, you were...
我认识的...
the best man...
最出色...最有人情味的人
the most human... human being that I've ever known
没有人能让我相信  你对我说的这一切都是在骗我
and no- one will ever convince me that you told me a lie, so...
就这样
there.
我好孤单
I was so alone...
我欠你好多
and I owe you so much.
但是  求你了  再求你一件事  就一件事
But, please, there's just one more thing, one more thing,
就一个奇迹  夏洛克  为了我  求你不要...
one more miracle, Sherlock, for me, don't be...
不要死
dead.
可以吗  就当是为了我
Would you do that just for me?
别这样  不要这么对我
Just stop it. Stop this.
新福尔摩斯 第2季 第3集
Sherlock S02E03 720p hdtv x264
YYeTs人人影视